Grant T. Reynard Papers
Grant T. Reynard Papers
1930-1966
Reynard, Grant T., 1887-1968.
2.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American etcher, lithographer, painter.
Correspondence (1930-1965); a subject file including exhibition catalogs, financial and legal material, and photographs; and published material by and about Reynard (1932-1965).
149540
Biographical History
Grant T. Reynard (1887-1968) was an American artist and illustrator. His illustrations appeared in many national magazines, including Saturday Evening Post, Country Gentleman, Ladies' Home Journal, Cosmopolitan, Harper's Bazaar, Collier's, McCall's, and many more.
Grant Tyson Reynard was born October 20, 1887, at Grand Island, Nebraska, to Stephen Blackstone and Jennie Lynd (Bacon) Reynard. He studied at the Chicago Art Institute, 1906-1907, and Chicago Academy of Fine Arts, 1908-1911. He established himself as an illustrator in New York and for ten years contributed to leading magazines. His increasing interest in painting, etching, and lithography took him to the chief centers of study in Europe, especially to Paris and London. After his return to America, he spent eight summers painting and etching at the MacDowell Colony in New Hampshire. His work is in the Metropolitan, Fogg, Newark, Norton, Addison, and Montclair Art Museums as well as the Library of Congress and New Public Library, and he had one-man shows at the Addison Museum, Montclair Art Museum, Andover, Kennedy and Company, New York, Grand Central Galleries, Clayton Gallery, and Association of American Artists, New York
Reynard served six years on the faculty of the Grand Central School of Art, New York, conducted the Department of Art at Millbrook School, Millbrook, New York, was artist-in-residence at Palo Duro School of Art in Texas, and taught two summers at the University of Texas. He lectured on art to many colleges and clubs, and was a member of the National Academy of Design, Salmagundi Club, Allied Artists of America, New Jersey Water Color Society, Associated Artists of New Jersey, Society of American Graphic Artists, American Water Color Society, Audubon Artists, Prairie Print Makers, and American Artists Group. In 1955, Baldwin-Wallace College awarded him an honorary Doctor of Humane Letters (LHD).
Reynard was also a skilled pianist, the author of a book-length poem Rattling Home for Christmas, and a regular contributor of articles on art to Scribner's and other national magazines.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Grant T. Reynard Papers, dating from 1930 to 1966, consist of correspondence, subject files, and published material.
Correspondence is subdivided into incoming and outgoing. Incoming correspondence (1930-1965) consists of 152 letters, dating from 1930-1965. Many of the correspondents are officials of universities and colleges, museums and art associations, as well as artists Norman Kent, Mainbocher, Mahonri Young, and Harry Wickey. Outgoing correspondence consists of 30 letters dating from 1940-1965. Among the recipients are Norman Kent, editor of American Artist, and H. J. Smith, President of Baldwin Wallace College, Berea, Ohio. Correspondence of others consists of five letters dating from 1930 to 1963, and includes that of poets Frances Frost and Edwin Arlington Robinson.
Subject files, dating from 1930 to 1966, include citations and honors, contracts and financial matters, exhibitions, lectures, and material relating to the Edward MacDowell Colony (1930-1964). There is a folder on the Millbrook School, photographs and paintings by others, personal photographs, photographs of Reynard's paintings and illustrations, and a slide.
Published material includes 24 articles about Grant Reynard. Magazines represented include Art Digest, Prints, and American Artist. There are five articles by Grant Reynard which appeared in The Western Artist, Scribner's, and American Artist. Ten illustrations by Reynard appeared in various magazines, listed alphabetically by magazine name. Also included are 107 newspaper clippings about Reynard, dating from 1932-1965; ten clippings about others, dating from 1935-1952; and a book-length poem entitled Rattling Home for Christmas.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically, then chronologically; outgoing is arranged chronologically, then alphabetically. Correspondence of others is arranged alphabetically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically. Published material is arranged alphabetically by title.
Related Material
has the papers of a number of artists and illustrators. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Illustrators; Art -- Painters; Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953.; Fabri, Ralph, 1894-; Kent, Norman, 1903-1972.; Reynard, Grant T., 1887-1968.; Wickey, Harry.; Young, Mahonri Mackintosh, 1877-1957.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Etchers -- United States.; Lithographers -- United States.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Articles.; Brochures.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Artists.; Etchers.; Lithographers.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Abbott Kimball Co., Inc., 1947 (Box 1)
    - Clifford O. Adams, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1934; 1936-1937; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Adult School of Montclair, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Grace A. Albee, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Woody Allen, 1952 (Box 1)
    - E. D. Alyea, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Amarillo College, 1955 (Box 1)
    - American Artist, 1947; 2 items (Box 1)
    - American Artists Group, Inc., 1956 (Box 1)
    - The American Federation of Arts, 1931 (Box 1)
    - American Watercolor Society, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Appalachian Mountain Club, 1953 (Box 1)
    - John Taylor Arms, 1952 (Box 1)
    - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1950 (Box 1)
    - The Art Students League of New York, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Associated Artists of New Jersey, undated (Box 1)
    - Association of American Colleges, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Baldwin-Wallace College, 1955; 1960; 6 items (Box 1)
    - Carl Beetz, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Fiske Boyd, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1955; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1944; 1946-1947; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Willa Cather Pioneer Memorial, 1956; 1964; 2 items (Box 1)
    - National Collier, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Columbia University, 1940; 1948,; 1958; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Henry K. Dick, 1950-1951; 2 items (Box 1)
    - Dickinson College, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Drexel Institute of Technology, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Everhart Museum, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Ralph Fabri, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Fairleigh Dickinson College, 1954 (Box 1)
    - "Fred", undated (Box 1)
    - Clayton E. Freeman, 1954; 1955; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Bronson Goddard, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Edmund Greacen, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Bob "Gwathney", 1961 (Box 1)
    - Hackley School, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Charles Hargens, 1956 (Box 1)
    - John Hartell, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Morris Harvey College, undated (Box 1)
    - Houghton College, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Arthur Hunter, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Leotine Huntsman, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Roma Ives, (1955) (Box 1)
    - KRNT, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Kennedy Co., 1940 (Box 1)
    - "Kent", 1955; 2 items (Box 1)
    - Norman Kent, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Helen S. Klahr, 1934 (Box 1)
    - The Joe and Emily Lowe Art Gallery, 1962 (Box 1)
    - The Edward MacDowell Association, Inc., 1959; 1963 (Box 1)
    - The MacDowell Colony, 1956; (1962); 3 items (Box 1)
    - Robert G. McIntyre, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Mainbocher, undated (Box 1)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 1)
    - Millbrook School, 1965 (Box 1)
    - The Montclair Art Museum, 1949-1951; 1956,; 1958; 5 items (Box 1)
    - Montclair Library, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1932-1933; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Melanie Martha Muller, 1935 (Box 1)
    - New Jersey Water Color Society, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Newark Museum, 1934; undated; 4 items (Box 1)
    - The New York Public Library, 1932-1933; 1937; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Agnes B. Noyes, undated (Box 1)
    - Joseph H. Oliphant & Company, 1955-1956; 1961-1962,; 1965; 5 items (Box 1)
    - Orange County Community College, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Pearson and Eaton, Inc., 1957; 1960; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Prairie Print Makers, 1954 (Box 1)
    - The Print Makers Society of California, 1954; 2 items (Box 1)
    - The Public Library of Newark, New Jersey, 1940 (Box 1)
    - Marian Ragan, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Edna Y. Searles, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Shelburne Museum, Inc., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Simpson College, 1953; 1955; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Jacob Getlar Smith, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 1959-1960; 2 items (Box 1)
    - South Dakota State College, 1956 (Box 1)
    - The Stony Brook School, 1954; 2 items (Box 1)
    - Mary Cwoke Swartwout, 1952; 1955; 2 items (Box 1)
    - Sweet Briar College, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Kenneth Thompson, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Town Hall, 1957 (Box 1)
    - The University of Buffalo, 1933; 2 items (Box 1)
    - The University of Nebraska, 1942 (Box 1)
    - The University of Wyoming, 1945-1946; 1948-1949; 8 items (Box 1)
    - The White House, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Harry Wickey, 1947-1948; 1950-1951; 4 items (Box 1)
    - The Wilmington Society of the Fine Arts, 1956; 1963; 2 items (Box 1)
    - Louis A. Wuerth, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Mahonri Young, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1940 (Box 1)
    - 1947, 2 items (Box 1)
    - 1949, 3 items (Box 1)
    - 1952-1956, 13 items (Box 1)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1962, 7 items (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - undated, 2 items (Box 1)
  - Of others
    - Katherine Disser to Miss Eaton, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Frances Frost to Hunter House Children, undated (Box 1)
    - Mrs. Thornton Hill to Mrs. Eaton, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Philip James to Mrs. Colwell, 1963 (Box 1)
    - E. A. Robinson to Dr. [Cushman], 1930 (Box 1)
- Subject file
  - Associated Artists of New Jersey, 1955; 1960,; 1963; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Bulwark of Liberty, Early Days at Dickinson, Volume 1, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Citations and Honors, 1955-1963 (Box 2)
  - Contracts and Financial Matters, 1929-1961 (Box 2)
  - Exhibitions 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Lectures flyers and brochures, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - The Edward MacDowell Colony, 1930; 1937-1938,; 1946,; 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Millbrook School, 1937; 1939-1941; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 items (Box 3)
  - Montclair Art Museum Bulletin, 1937; 1961,; 1964-1966; 16 items (Box 3)
  - "Oneone, and Eight Other Tone-Pictures," Louis M. Elshems (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - Paintings by others, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Personal, 74 items (Box 3)
    - Grant Reynard's Paintings and Illustrations (Box 3)
  - Pictures on exhibit, March 1938 (Box 3)
  - Publicity flyers and material, 16 items (Box 3)
  - Reproductions of Illustrations, 3 items (Box 3)
  - Slide (Box 3)
- Published material
  - Articles about, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Articles by, 5 items (Box 4)
  - Illustrations by, 10 items (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - About Reynard, 1932-1965; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - About others, 1935-1952 (Box 5)
  - Poem, "Rattling Home for Christmas", American Artists Group, Inc., 1941 (Box 5)